纽约
2012年
搜索救援由我来指挥
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
这样说话 你们也受得了
I mean, honestly, how do you keep your food down?
闭嘴
Shut up.
-嘿！ 嘿 哥们儿！
-Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey, hey. Buddy!
你想干吗？你上来电梯非超重不可
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
-去走楼梯吧 没错 别上来了
2012 THOR: Take the stairs. -2012 STARK: Yeah. Stop, stop.
把箱子交出来 史塔克
AGENT: Hand over the case, Stark.
把箱子给我
-Hand it over.
-史塔克？ 史塔克？
PIERCE: Stark? 2012 THOR: Stark?
深呼吸 深呼吸
Breathe, breathe.
干得好 我们在小巷见 我先吃口东西
STARK: Good job. Meet me in the alley. I'm gonna grab a quick slice.
不要 楼梯
No stairs!
洛基呢？
2012 THOR: Where's Loki?
洛基
Loki! Loki!
蒙古戈壁沙漠
我是阿斯加德的洛基
I am Loki of Asgard.
我肩负着光荣的使命
And I am burdened with glorious purpose.
你是谁？
你来我们这干什么？
我…
I. . .
无所谓了
Never mind.
别碰那个
Don't touch that.
看来是标准时序侵犯
Appears to be a standard sequence violation.
时间分支发展速度斜率稳定
Branch is growing at a stable rate and slope.
发现时间犯
Variant identified.
你说什么
I beg your pardon.
代表时间变异管理局
On behalf of the Time Variance Authority,
我以侵犯神圣时间线的罪名逮捕你
I hereby arrest you for crimes against the Sacred Timeline.
举起手来
Hands up.
跟我们走
You're coming with us.
不好意思 〝我们〞指的是谁？
I'm sorry. Who's "us"?
最后一次警告 时间犯
Last chance, Variant.
这一天真是没完没了
It's been a very long day,
我受够了全副武装的白痴 对我指手画脚
and I think I've had my fill of idiots in armored suits telling me what to do,
所以不好意思 是我最后一次警告你们
so, if you don't mind, this is actually your last chance.
给我让开
Now get out of my way.
你现在身处1/16的速度中
You are now moving at 1/16th speed,
但是痛感是实际的时间长度
but feeling all that pain in real time.
重置时间线
Reset the timeline.
-什么种族？ 斯库鲁时间犯
MAN 1: What species? MAN 2: Variant Skrull.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
我爸爸是高盛董事会的
My dad is on the board of Goldman Sachs.
他打个电话 你的工作就玩完了
One call and your whole job is privatized.
-好吧 你觉得怎么样？
MAN 3 : All right. MAN 4: How'd you like that?
你好 先生
MAN 1: Hello, sir.
-来吧 你犯了个严重的错误
-HUNTER B-15: Come on. You're making a terrible mistake.
你完全搞错了
MAN 4: You're making a big mistake. Whoa!
-你好 女士. . . 把这个记录为证物
-Hello, ma'am, uh. . . HUNTER B-15: Log this as evidence.
你能至少告诉我这是什么吗？
Oh. . . Can you at least tell me what it is?
这是宇宙魔方 小心点
It's the Tesseract. Be very careful with it.
听上去很蠢
MAN: It sounds dumb.
听好了
Know this.
你跟我作对 下场会很难看
You cross me, there are deadly consequences.
我等着看
We'll see.
Hey, hey!
你休想
Absolutely not.
这可是上等的阿斯加德皮革
This is fine Asgardian leather.
别动
Hold very still.
你等一下
Now, hang on just a minute.
请签字确认这是你全部说过的话
Please sign to verify this is everything you've ever said.
什么？
What?
这个也得签
Sign this, too.
什么？
这太荒谬了
Oh, this is absurd.
还有这个
And this.
请确认你自知不是机器人
Please confirm to your knowledge that you are not a fully robotic being,
而是有机生物
were born an organic creature,
并拥有许多文明称之为灵魂的事物
and do in fact possess what many cultures would call a soul.
什么？我自知？
What? "To my knowledge"?
很多人不知道自己是机器人吗？
Do a lot of people not know if they're robots?
谢谢你的确认 请走过去
Thank you for confirming. Move through.
如果我是机器人但是自己不知道呢？
What if I was a robot and I didn't know it?
机器会将你完全熔化
The machine would melt you from the inside out.
继续移动 先生
Please move along, sir.
好吧 我不是机器人 我没事
Okay, I'm not a robot, so I'll be fine.
什么？
What?
-那是什么？ 你的现世光环
-LOKI: Oh, what's that? Your temporal aura.
-那是什么？ 请进去吧
-What's that? Please, through the door.
拿一张票
Take a ticket.
这是什么地方？速食店吗？不
What is this, a deli? No.
拿一张票
Take a ticket.
这一共就两个人
There's only two of us in here.
拿一张票
MINUTEMAN: Take a ticket.
你们搞错了 我不应该来这里
This is a mistake! I shouldn't be here!
你好 你可能觉得
Hey there! You're probably saying,
你们搞错了 我不应该来这里
"This is a mistake. I shouldn't even be here. "
欢迎来到时间变异管理局
Welcome to the Time Variance Authority.
我是时间小姐
I'm Miss Minutes,
我的职责就是 在你接受审判前 让你明白一些事情
and it's my job to catch you up before you stand trial for your crimes.
咱们别浪费时间啦
So let's not waste another minute.
坐好 拿起笔 听我讲
Settle in, sharpen your pencils, and check this out.
很久以前 有一场多元宇宙大战
Long ago, there was a vast multiversal war.
无数的时间线互相纷争 争夺霸权
Countless unique timelines battled each other for supremacy,
几乎完全毁灭了一切
nearly resulting in the total destruction of. . .
. . . well, everything.
就在那时 全知全能的 时间守护者出现了
But then, the all-knowing Time-Keepers emerged,
他们将多元宇宙合并为一条时间线 从而恢复了和平
bringing peace by reorganizing the multiverse into a single timeline,
这就是神圣时间线
the Sacred Timeline.
现在 时间守护者维护着世间万物
Now, the Time-Keepers protect and preserve the proper flow of time
确保着时间的正常流动
for everyone and everything.
但是有时 会有像你一样的人 偏离时间守护者设定的路径
But sometimes, people like you veer off the path the Time-Keepers created.
这些人就是时间犯
We call those Variants.
可能是你领头反抗 也可能就是上班迟到
Maybe you started an uprising, or were just late for work.
不管什么原因 偏离路径 就会造成关连事件
Whatever it was, stepping off your path created a nexus event,
如果不及时处理 就会引发混乱
which, left unchecked, could branch off into madness,
最终导致另一场多元宇宙大战
-leading to another multiversal war.
危险：多元宇宙
但不用担心
But, don't worry,
为了避免这种情况
to make sure that doesn't happen,
时间守护者创造了时间变异管理局 还有一群杰出的工作者
the Time-Keepers created the TVA and all its incredible workers.
时间变异管理局会介入并修复错误
The TVA has stepped in to fix your mistake
把时间重置到预定的路径中
and set time back on its predetermined path.
如果你的行径导致自己 不能回到原有的时间线上
Now that your actions have left you without a place on the timeline,
你就必须要为自己的罪行接受审判
you must stand trial for your offenses.
请坐好 我们会立刻为你安排法官
So sit tight, and we'll get you in front of a judge in no time.
确保你拿好了自己的票
Just make sure you have your ticket,
下一位有空的助理会接待你
and you'll be seen by the next available attendant.
时间变异管理局 永恒常相伴
-For all time. PEOPLE: Always.
时间变异管理局 叙事委员会
时间守护者？神圣时间线？
Time-Keepers? The Sacred Timeline?
谁会相信这种胡扯
Who actually believes this bunkum?
-你的票呢？ 先生 他没给我票 我要了
-MINUTEMAN: Ticket, sir? He didn't give me a ticket. I asked.
-你的票 先生 我找那个家伙要票了
-Ticket, sir! I tried to ask that guy for a ticket!
先生…
Sir. . .
你敢朝我大喊大叫 锅盖头？
What, you're raising your voice at me, bucket head?
感谢到访时间变异管理局
MISS MINUTES: Thanks for visiting the TVA.
请为我们的服务留下宝贵评价
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.
《洛基》
法国 普罗旺斯地区艾克斯
追捕者和时间卫士 正在处理例行的关连事件
The hunter and his Minutemen responded to a routine nexus event.
他们到达现场时 遭到了伏击
It appears that when they arrived, somebody got the jump on 'em.
你觉得呢？
You think?
是他
HUNTER U-92: It's him.
没错 这刺伤和其它的一模一样
Yeah, stab wounds look consistent with the others.
尸体的位置表明 他们不知道是谁袭击了他们
Positioning of the bodies indicates they didn't know what the hell hit 'em.
重置设备也不见了
And reset charge is gone.
这是上周的第六次袭击
That's the sixth attack in the last week.
还只是已知的
That we know of.
-嘿 等等 后退 后退
-Hey! Wait, stand down! Stand down.
只是个孩子而已
It's just a kid.
对不起
我的朋友是个笨蛋
我也会说这条时间线上 所有的语言
HUNTER U-92: Hey, yo!
笨蛋
按一下
Tap it.
你知道是谁干的吗？
别担心 那个魔鬼害怕我们
Don't worry, that devil's afraid of us.
我们会解决他的
We're gonna take care of him.
并送你回到你该去地方
And we're gonna put you back where you belong.
那个蓝色. . .
那是什么？
带着礼物的恶魔
Devil bearing gifts.
继续搜索序列周期 寻找现世光环的迹象
Go ahead and run this for sequence period and any hints of temporal aura.
你知道这是徒劳的
You know we won't get anything.
没错 试试看吧
Yeah, just give it a shot.
这个分支已经接近红线了 咱们得撤了
HUNTER U-92: The branch is nearing red line. We need to go.
好吧
Okay.
去外面等着
没事的
It's okay.
设定重置器
HUNTER U-92: Set a reset charge.
长官 有些东西你得看看
Sir, there's something you'll wanna see.
已逮捕
下一个案件
JUDGE: Next case, please.
劳菲森 L1130号时间犯 又名洛基·劳菲森
Laufeyson. Variant L1130, AKA Loki Laufeyson,
你被指控侵犯序列7-20-89
is charged with sequence violation 7-20-89.
你有何申辩？
How do you plead?
女士 神是不会申辩的
Madam, a god doesn't plead.
这出荒诞剧很有意思 但是我得走了
This has been a very enjoyable pantomime, but I'd like to go home now.
你是有罪还是无罪 先生？
Are you guilty or not guilty, sir?
作为诡计之神而有罪？可以
Guilty of being the God of Mischief? Yes.
觉得这一切枯燥乏味而有罪？也可以
Guilty of finding all this incredibly tedious? Yes.
侵犯神圣时间线的罪名？
Guilty of a crime against the Sacred Timeline?
绝对不可能 你们抓错人了
Absolutely not, you have the wrong person.
真的吗？ 那我们应该抓谁？
Oh, really? And who should we have?
我觉得应该抓复仇者联盟
I suspect, the Avengers.
我能拿到宇宙魔方 都是因为他们的时间旅行
I came into possession of the Tesseract because they traveled through time,
他们绞尽脑汁就是为了 阻止我成为神圣帝王
no doubt in a last-ditch effort to stave off my ascent to God King.
这指控可不小啊
That's quite an accusation.
相信我 你都能闻到两个史塔克 身上的香水味
LOKI: Oh, believe me, you can smell the cologne of two Tony Starks.
你要找时间犯？ 他们才是时间犯
You speak of Time Criminals? It's they you should be after.
如果你给我一支军队和足够的资源
Perhaps you could provide me with a taskforce and resources,
我就能回去把他们消灭掉
and I could return and eliminate them for you.
我们现在说的不是复仇者联盟
We're not here to talk about the Avengers.
-不是吗？ 不是
-Oh, no? No.
他们的所作所为是应该发生的 但是你的逃脱不是
What they did was supposed to happen. You escaping was not.
好吧
Right. Uh. . .
不应该发生？谁规定的？
"Not supposed to happen"? According to whom?
时间守护者？
The Time-Keepers?
时间守护者啊 好吧
Oh, the Time-Keepers. Right.
好吧 也许我应该直接和 这些时间守护者进行神之间的对话
Well, perhaps I should speak to these Time-Keepers, gods to gods.
对不起 他们很忙
I'm sorry, but they're quite busy.
他们忙？他们在干什么？
Oh, they are? What are they doing?
规定时间的正确流动
Dictating the proper flow of time.
我明白了 好吧 那你们是干什么的？
I see. Right. And then what do you do?
按照他们的规定 来规定时间的正确流动
Dictate the proper flow of time according to their dictations.
你有何申辩？
How do you plead?
我的罪名. . .
Guilty. . .
就是这个
of this.
-他在干什么？ 等等 大家安静
-What's going on? LOKI: Hang on. Everyone quiet.
-他在试图使用他的力量 女士 别逼我
-He's trying to use his powers, ma'am. Don't rush me.
该死 为什么不起作用？
Damn it! Why won't it work?
魔法力量？在时间变异管理局这里无效 劳菲森先生
Magic powers? They're no good in the TVA, Mr. Laufeyson.
本庭认定你罪名成立 并判你重置
The court finds you guilty, and I sentence you to be reset.
下一个案件
Next case, please!
重置？那是什么意思？ 是坏结果吗？什么意思？
"Reset"? What does that mean? What, is it bad? What does it mean?
你们这些荒谬的官僚 你们无权决定我的结局
Hey! You ridiculous bureaucrats will not dictate how my story ends!
这不是你的结局 劳菲森先生 它和你根本没有关系
It's not your story, Mr. Laufeyson. It never was.
你们不知道我能干些什么
You have no idea what I'm capable of!
我想我知道
MAN: I. . . I think I might.
我知道他能干些什么
Have an idea of what he's capable of.
近前说话
Approach the bench.
你好
Hi.
如果我没猜错 那可不是什么好主意
If you're thinking what I think you are, it's a bad idea.
我只是在寻找一种可能性
Okay, I'm just chasing a hunch.
出了任何差错 都是你的责任
Anything goes sideways, it's on you.
没问题 我可是一直都仰视您的
Okay. I feel like I'm always looking up to you.
我很乐意 本该如此
I like it. It's appropriate.
你又是谁？
And who are you?
我要把这个地方烧成灰烬
I'm gonna burn this place to the ground.
我告诉你我的办公桌在哪 你可以从那烧起
I'll show you where my desk is, you can start there.
看看吧
Have a look.
回家真好
Home sweet home.
我还以为这里没有魔法
I thought there was no magic here.
确实没有
There isn't.
这都不是真的
That's not real.
不幸的是 这是真的 那些文书工作也是
It is, and, unfortunately, so is all the paperwork.
倒是不错的放火材料 来吧
Good tinder for your fire, though. Come on.
这地方就是个噩梦
This place is a nightmare.
那是另一个部门
That's another department.
那个部门我可以帮你一起烧
Now that department I'll help you burn down.
我是莫比乌斯探员
I'm Agent Mobius, by the way.
你是要把我带到什么地方杀掉吗？
Are you taking me somewhere to kill me?
不是 刚才的地方才会 我要带你去个地方谈谈
No. That's where you just were. I'm taking you some place to talk.
我不想说话
I don't like to talk.
但是你喜欢说谎 你刚刚就说了一个
But you do like to lie, which you just did.
我们都知道你喜欢说话
Because we both know you love to talk.
没完没了
Talkie-talkie.
你在这多长时间了
How long have you been here?
我不知道 很难说 时间变异管理局的时间流动不太一样
I don't know. It's hard to say, time passes differently here in the TVA.
-那是什么意思？ 你会明白的
-What does that mean? You'll catch up.
所以你就是时间变异管理局 勤劳勇敢的工作人员？
LOKI: So, you're part of the TVA's courageous and dedicated workforce?
是的
Yes.
-你是时间守护者创造的？ 是的
-You were created by the Time-Keepers. Yep.
-为了保护神圣时间线 没错
-To protect the Sacred Timeline. Correct.
很搞笑吗？
Is that funny?
你们这个小破地方 主宰着世间无数人的命运
The idea that your little club decides the fate of trillions of people
听命于三个太空蜥蜴
across all of existence at the behest of three space lizards,
确实挺搞笑的
yes, it's funny.
这太荒谬了
It's absurd.
我以为你不想说话呢
I thought you didn't like to talk.
你先请
After you.
话说回来 这地方真的像是 要把我杀掉的地方
For the record, this really does feel like a killing-me kind of a room.
你不怎么信任别人 是不是
Not big on trust, are you?
只有小孩子和狗才会信任别人
Trust is for children and dogs.
只有一个人你能信任
There's only one person you can trust.
你自己？我喜欢这个想法
MOBIUS: Yourself? I like it.
可以印在T恤上
Slap it on a T-shirt.
如果时间变异管理局一直在监视着
If the TVA truly oversees all of time,
我怎么之前从来没听说过？
how have I never heard of you until now?
因为没那个必要
'Cause you've never needed to.
你一直在设定好的路径里
You've always lived within your set path.
我想在哪条路径 就在哪条路径
I live within whatever path I choose.
当然可以 好吧 请坐
MOBIUS: Sure you do. Okay, come have a seat.
我告诉过你 在时间变异管理局 时间的流动不太一样
I told you, time moves differently in the TVA.
来吧 请坐
Come on, sit down.
咱们准备开始
Let's get into this.
来吧 请坐
Go on, have a seat.
你的眼神能杀人
If looks could kill.
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
咱们先来一点小小的合作
Well, let's start with a little cooperation.
我可不擅长
Not my forte.
真的吗？
Really?
即便是在你一边示好 一边准备背叛的时候？
Even when you're wooing someone powerful you intend to betray?
来吧
Come on.
你对我一无所知
You don't know anything about me.
也许我愿意学呢
Maybe I'd like to learn.
我的专长是追踪那些 危险的时间犯
I specialize in the pursuit of dangerous Variants.
比如我自己？
Like myself?
不 是特别危险的时间犯
Mmm. . . No, particularly dangerous Variants.
你就是只小猫咪
You're just a little pussycat.
我有些问题要问你
I got a set of questions for you.
如果你能诚实回答
You answer them honestly,
也许我可以给你想要的东西
and then maybe I can give you something you want.
你想从这里出去 是不是？
You wanna get out of here, right?
没错 那我们开始吧
Yeah, so we'll start there.
你要是能回去 你要去干什么？
Should you return, what are you gonna do?
-完成我已经开始的事情 那是什么？
-Finish what I started. Which is?
确立我的王位
Claim my throne.
你想成为国王？
You wanna be king?
我不是想成为国王 我生而为王
I don't want to be, I was born to be.
我知道 但是具体是什么国王呢？
I know, but king of what exactly?
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
说来听听
Try me.
米德加德
Midgard.
也就是地球
AKA Earth.
好吧 现在你是米德加德的国王了 然后呢？
All right. Now you're the king of Midgard, then what?
幸福地生活下去了？
Happily ever after?
然后是阿斯加德 以及全部九界
Asgard, the Nine Realms.
-全宇宙？ 全宇宙？
-Space? Space?
宇宙那么大 那可是不小的成就啊
Space is big. That'd be a nice feather in your cap.
洛基 宇宙之王
"Loki, the King of Space. "
你嘲讽我一个试试
Mock me if you dare.
不 我没有
No, I'm not.
其实我可是个粉丝
Honestly, I'm actually a fan. Yeah.
我不明白 为什么一个人 有这么大能力 却只想统治
And I guess I'm wondering why does someone with so much range just wanna rule?
我会让他们更加轻松
I would've made it easy for them.
人们喜欢轻松
People like easy.
史上第一个也是最大的谎言
The first and most oppressive lie ever uttered
就是自由的意志
was the song of freedom.
这是从何说起？
How's that one go?
对于几乎所有的生命而言
For nearly every living thing,
选择滋生的就是羞耻 不确定性和悔恨
choice breeds shame and uncertainty and regret.
每条道路都凶险无比
There's a fork in every road,
人们总是选择错误的道路
yet the wrong path always taken.
说得好
Good. Yeah.
你说 几乎所有的生命
You said "nearly every living thing, "
也就是说 你不在其中
so I'm guessing you don't fall into that category?
时间守护者建造了一个大马戏团
The Time-Keepers have built quite the circus,
你们这些小丑 在完美地诠释着自己的角色
and I see the clowns are playing their parts to perfection.
你这个满嘴隐喻的家伙 我挺喜欢的
Big metaphor guy. I love it.
听上去很聪明的样子
Makes you sound super smart.
我就是聪明
I am smart.
我知道
I know.
好吧
Okay.
这是什么？
What is this?
你生命中的重要时刻样本 我给你看看
A sampling of your greatest hits, if I may.
如果还可以的话
LOKI: If it's all the same to you. . .
我想喝那杯酒
I'll have that drink now.
不用了
No.
我记得 我就在那 还有其它的吗？
And I remember. I was there. Anything else?
很有趣 你这个天生统治的人 居然经常一败涂地
It's funny, for someone born to rule, you sure do lose a lot.
都快成你命中注定的了
You might even say it's in your nature.
你要知道 上一个和我这么说话的人 最后没什么好下场
You know, things didn't turn out so well for the last person who said that to me.
没错 菲尔·寇森
Oh, yeah, Phil Coulson.
不
THOR: No!
复仇者联盟不是一起打败了你 为他复仇了吗？
Didn't the Avengers come together to literally avenge him by defeating you?
对于一个死人而言小小的慰藉罢了
Little solace to a dead man.
你喜欢伤害别人吗？
Do you enjoy hurting people?
让他们觉得自己渺小
Making them feel small?
让他们心存恐惧
Making them feel afraid?
-你的把戏吓不到我 让他们感觉微不足道
-Your games don't frighten me. Making them feel little?
我知道我是谁
I know what I am.
-一个凶手？ 一个解放者
-A murderer? A liberator.
解放的是眼球吧
Of eyeballs, maybe.
看看那个笑容 你真是乐在其中
MOBIUS: Look at that smile. You are enjoying that.
你喜欢伤害他们吗？
Did you enjoy hurting them?
我没必要跟你玩下去 我是神
I don't have to play this game. I'm a god.
什么神来着？诡计是吗？
Of what, again? Mischief, right?
我没看出这里有什么诡计
Yeah. I don't see anything very mischievous about this.
你确实看不出来
No, I don't suppose you do.
咱们来聊聊你的逃跑吧
Let's talk about your escapes.
你真的很擅长做些可怕的事 然后自己脱身
You're really good at doing awful things, and then just getting away.
那又怎么样？我可是诡计多端的骗子
What can I say? I'm a mischievous scamp.
这是我最喜欢的片段之一
This is one of my favorites.
这里是驾驶舱 我是机长威廉·A·斯科特
From the flight deck, Captain William A. Scott,
西北东方航空305号班机 飞往西雅图
Northwest Orient Airlines 305, on schedule to land in Seattle.
今天的飞行时间大约是. . .
Flight time today, approximately. . .
波本威士忌配苏打水？
Bourbon and soda?
谢谢
Thank you.
没问题 还有什么需要我做的吗 先生？
FLIGHT ATTENDANT: Absolutely. Is there anything else I can do for you, sir?
我想咱们都知道 是不是？
I suppose we'll find out, won't we?
-小姐 怎么 库珀先生？
-Uh, Miss? Yes, Mr. Cooper?
你最好看看那张纸条
You might want to take a look at that note.
我带了炸弹
I have a bomb.
我看不出来这有什么关系. . .
I fail to see how this has any relevance or bearing on. . .
不 这是最精彩的部分
No. This is the good part.
改天再见
See you again someday.
哥哥 海姆达尔 你们等着
Brother, Heimdall, you better be ready.
我不敢相信你居然是D·B·库珀 真的吗
I can't believe you were D. B. Cooper. Come on!
我那时还年轻 而且和索尔打输了赌
I was young, and I lost a bet to Thor.
我在胡搞这些的时候 时间管理局在哪里？
Where was the TVA when I was meddling with these affairs of men?
我们就在那里 在神圣时间线上
We were right there with you, just surfing that Sacred Timeline.
所以时间守护者允许那些事发生是吗？
So that had the Time-Keepers' seal of approval, did it?
我觉得和允许不允许没什么关系
Well, I wouldn't think of it in terms of approval and disapproval.
那是一种. . .
That's sort of a. . .
咱们还是回来继续聊逃跑吧 还有些心理问题
Let's get back to escapes. . . . . . and a little psychobabble.
你觉得自己在逃避些什么？
What is it that you think that you're really running from?
够了
Enough.
回来坐好
Back in your cage.
看 我也不是吃素的
See, I can play the heavy keys, too.
我只是要站起来发表一个观点
I was just standing up to make a point.
对不起 你继续
I'm sorry, go ahead.
现在没意义了
It won't be as meaningful now.
好吧 那就继续坐着
Okay, well, stay seated.
我想干什么就干什么
I'll do what I want to do!
当然
Sure.
你到底想要什么？
What exactly is it that you want?
我想让你诚实面对为什么要做那些事
I want you to be honest about why you do what you do.
骗子
Liar.
我很认真的
I'm serious.
我想深入挖掘恐怖的诡计之神 内心的真实想法
All I seek is a deeper understanding of the fearsome God of Mischief.
是什么在驱使着洛基?
What makes Loki tick?
-我知道这是什么地方了 什么地方？
-I know what this place is. What is it?
都是幻像
It's an illusion.
这是一个残酷而又精心设计的骗局 由弱者操纵的制造恐惧的工具
It's a cruel, elaborate trick conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
是为了掌控他人的一场疯狂试验
A desperate attempt at control.
你们在这里走来走去
Now, you all parade about
仿佛自己是宇宙中至高无上的仲裁
as if you're the divine arbiters of power in the universe.
-我们就是 你们不是
-We are. You're not.
我的选择是我自己的
My choices are my own.
你的选择就是你的 没问题 咱们继续吧
Your choice is your own. Good, let's go with that.
我觉得这个你看了肯定兴奋
I think this one's gonna fire you up.
自由的诱惑剥夺了你们人生中的快乐
The bright lure of freedom diminishes your life's joy
你们疯狂地追求权势
in a mad scramble for power. . .
没错
Precisely.
我. . .
I was. . .
我差一点就得到了我本该得到的一切
I am on the verge of acquiring everything I am owed,
我能得到是因为我的所作所为
and when I do, it'll be because I did it.
而不是因为它本该如此
Not because it was supposed to happen.
也不是因为你或时间变异管理局
Or because you or the Time Variance Authority,
或者什么你们自称的玩意的允许
or whatever it is you call yourselves, allowed me to.
说实话 你挺可悲的
Honestly, you're pathetic.
你是个无关紧要的存在
You're an irrelevance.
多余的存在
A detour.
我前进路上的脚注
A footnote to my ascent.
你说完了吗？
You finished?
你得开始认真对待这一切
You're gonna start taking things seriously.
如果你没有拿起宇宙魔方
If you hadn't picked up the Tesseract,
你就会被关押在阿斯加德的牢房里
you would have been taken to a cell on Asgard.
洛基
Loki.
你好 母亲
LOKI: Hello, Mother.
你为我感到骄傲吗？
Have I made you proud?
不要把事情变得更糟
Please don't make this worse.
这是什么？
What is this?
这是胡扯 这是骗局 这从来没发生过
This is nonsense, more tricks. This never even happened.
对于你没发生过
MOBIUS: Not to you.
还没有发生
Not yet.
时间变异管理局知道的不仅是你的过去
Look, the TVA doesn't just know your whole past,
我们知道你的一生会注定发生什么
we know your whole life, how it's all meant to be.
你可以当作是一种安慰
Think of it as comforting.
这太荒谬了
This is absurd.
我也不是你的母亲吗？
And am I not your mother?
你不是
LOKI: You're not.
FRIGGA: Hmm.
你好像已经把所有人都看透了 除了你自己以外
Always so perceptive about everyone but yourself.
然后黑暗精灵袭击了宫殿 你以为你把他们引到了索尔那边
MOBIUS: And then the Dark Elves attack the palace,
and you think you send them to Thor.
我觉得你应该走左侧的楼梯
You might wanna take the stairs to the left.
但其实 你把他们引去了. . .
But instead, you send them. . .
我不会告诉你
I'll never tell.
你们把她带到哪去了？她在哪？
Where do you have her? Where is she?
你把他们直接引去了她那里
You lead them right to her.
我不相信你 你在说谎 这不是真的
I don't believe you. You're lying. It's not true.
这是真的
It is true.
这是时间正确的流动
That's the proper flow of time,
它会一次又一次地发生 因为本该如此
and it happens again and again and again because it's supposed to,
因为必须如此
because it has to.
-时间变异管理局确保这一点 她在哪？
-The TVA makes sure of it. Where is she?
现在你为什么不告诉我 你喜欢伤害人吗？
Now why don't you tell me, do you enjoy hurting people?
-我不相信你 你喜欢杀戮吗？
-I don't believe you. Do you enjoy killing?
-我要杀了你 就像你对你母亲一样？
-I'll kill you. Like you did your mother?
抱歉 时间逆转器只倒转了你 没倒转椅子
Sorry, the Time Twister just loops you, not the furniture.
你并非生而为王 洛基
You weren't born to be king, Loki.
你的出生造成了痛苦 折磨和死亡
You were born to cause pain and suffering and death.
现在如此 过去如此 未来亦如此
That's how it is, that's how it was, that's how it will be.
这样其他人才能成就最辉煌的自我
All so that others can achieve their best versions of themselves.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
来吧
Come on.
你在干什么？
HUNTER B-15: What are you doing?
这是我的工作 你的工作就是打断别人吗？
My job. Is it yours to interrupt?
出状况了
We have a situation.
总是会出状况
There's always a situation.
哪也别去
Don't go anywhere.
一切渐入佳境 我正在兴头上
It was just getting good. Spirited.
-和那个时间犯交谈是个错误 那是你的立场
-Talking to that Variant is a mistake. That's your position.
他应该被重置
He should be reset!
你觉得每个人都应该被重置 我大有收获
You think everyone should be reset. I'm getting good stuff!
我们又失去了一支小队
We lost another unit.
好吧 洛基 我觉得咱们明天结束以后再. . .
Okay, Loki, I think we can finish up tomorrow and just pick it. . .
诡计多端的骗子
Mischievous scamp.
真希望我会对此感到意外
Wish I could say I was surprised.
-真希望你没有打断我们 我？这是我的错？
-Yeah, I wish you hadn't interrupted us. Me? It's my fault?
他不可能跑太远
Look, he can't have gotten very far.
分头行动 发现他后立刻裁减
HUNTER B-15: Split up. Prune on sight.
不 不要裁减 不要重置 他能帮助我们
No, no pruning, no resetting. He can still help us!
你好
Hey.
你好 我认识你
Hey. I know you.
你是那个带着蓝盒子的罪犯
-You're that criminal with the blue box.
你叫什么名字
-Ow. What's your name?
凯西
Casey.
给我宇宙魔方 否则我就像 刴鱼一样把你开肠破肚 凯西
Give me the Tesseract, or I'll gut you like a fish, Casey.
鱼是什么？
-What's a fish?
What's a fish?
你怎么连鱼是什么都不知道？
How do you not know what a fish is?
我这一辈子都在办公桌后面
I've lived my entire life behind a desk.
这有什么意义？
Well, what difference does it make?
在我顺从之前 我想确切地知道威胁是什么
I wanna know exactly what I'm being threatened with before I comply.
死亡 凯西 暴力的痛苦的死亡
Death, Casey. Violent, painful death.
好吧 好吧 我听你的
Okay, okay. I comply, I comply.
我听你的 天啊
I comply. Jeez!
Um. . . Oh.
是这个吗？
-CASEY: This it?
什么？
LOKI: What?
无限原石？
Infinity Stones?
怎么会. . .
How. . .
你们怎么会有这些？
How do you have these?
实际上我们有许多
Oh, We actually get a lot of those.
有些人拿来做镇纸
Yeah. Some of the guys use them as paperweights.
有些人吧
Some of 'em.
这里是全宇宙最强大的力量吗？
Is this the greatest power in the universe?
你差点打到我
CASEY: Oh, you almost hit me!
太过分了
That's so messed up.
分头行动 搜索下层大厅
HUNTER B-15: Split up. Check the lower concourse.
我不会原谅你的
CASEY: I do not forgive you.
我爱你们 我的孩子们
I love you, my sons.
记住这个地方
Remember this place.
家园
Home.
洛基 你对我很重要
Loki, I thought the world of you.
我觉得咱们俩能永远并肩作战
I thought we were gonna fight side by side forever.
我忽然觉得你并没那么坏 弟弟
Maybe you're not so bad after all, brother.
那可没准
Maybe not.
谢谢
THOR: Thank you.
你要是在我身边 我真想拥抱你
If you were here, I might even give you a hug.
我在这儿
LOKI: I'm here.
不死的？
THANOS: Undying?
你还真是大言不惭呢
You should choose your words more carefully.
你…
LOKI: You. . .
永远不会成为…
will never be. . .
真正的神
a god.
档案结束
什么这么好笑
HUNTER B-15: What's so funny?
光荣的使命
Glorious purpose.
住…
Stop. . .
手
It.
住手
Stop it!
St. . . Stop it. . .
It. . . Stop it. . .
Stop. . . I. . . St. . . Sto. . . St. . .
这家伙一直说要把我变成鱼
And this guy kept saying he was gonna turn me into a fish,
不管那是什么
whatever that is,
然后他们就出现了 裁减了我的推车
and then they show up and just prune my cart,
我什么都干不了了
so there was nothing I could have done.
就是你
Hey, there you are.
你知道吗 那个时间犯逃跑了
You know, that Variant you had got away.
洛基？
MOBIUS: Loki?
你无路可逃了
Nowhere left to run.
我回不去了 是不是？
I can't go back, can I?
回到我的时间线
Back to my timeline.
我不喜欢伤害人
I don't enjoy hurting people.
我. . .
I. . .
我不喜欢
I don't enjoy it.
我那么做是因为我必须那么做
I do it because I have to,
因为我别无选择
because I've had to.
好吧 和我说说
Okay, explain that to me.
因为这是幻象的一部分
Because it's part of the illusion.
这是一个残酷而又精心设计的骗局 一个弱者操纵的制造恐惧的工具
It's the cruel, elaborate trick conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
是为了掌控他人的疯狂行径
A desperate play for control.
你还挺了解自己的
You do know yourself.
我是一个坏人
A villain.
我倒不这么觉得
That's not how I see it.
你试着用了？
You try to use that?
用了好几次
Oh, several times.
即使是无限原石在这里也没用
Even an Infinity Stone is useless here.
时间变异管理局真是令人敬畏
The TVA is formidable.
这就是我的感受
MOBIUS: That's been my experience.
听着 我不能给你救赎
Listen, I can't offer you salvation,
但是也许我可以给你更好的
but maybe I can offer you something better.
一个在逃的时间犯在杀害我们的时间卫士
A fugitive Variant's been killing our Minutemen.
你需要诡计之神来帮你制止他？
And you need the God of Mischief to help you stop him?
没错
That's right.
为什么是我？
Why me?
因为我们在追捕的时间犯就是. . .
The Variant we're hunting is. . .
你
you.
你说什么？
I beg your pardon?
俄克拉荷马州 萨莱纳
1858年
时间标记是第三个千年初期 绝对不符合时间线
MINUTEMAN: Time signature is early third millennium.
Definitely anachronistic.
是石油
Oil.
我认为这个混蛋找到了一台时间机器
I think some jackass found himself a time machine,
为了发财回到这里
came back here to get rich.
我们要展开追捕吗 长官？
Should we fan out and look for him, sir?
不了 还不够咱们写文书的呢
Nah. It's not worth the paperwork.
裁减掉吧 咱们走 设置重置器
Just prune it. Let's bail. Set a charge.
等等 有人在那
MINUTEMAN: Wait. Someone's out there.
去看看
Check it out.
后退
HUNTER U-92: Get down!
根据漫威漫画改编
漫威影业 出品
《洛基》
感谢到访时间变异管理局
MISS MINUTES: Thanks for visiting the TVA.
请为我们的服务留下宝贵评价
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.
字幕翻译：虫二